Guide to the Tompkins County American Red Cross records. 1917-2012
Tompkins County American Red Cross records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Tompkins County American Red Cross records. 1917-2012
6985
Tompkins County American Red Cross.
8.8 cubic feet.
Correspondence, photographs, scrapbooks
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes minutes of meetings, scrapbooks, ledgers, memos, photographs, awards, and correspondence.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes minutes of meetings, scrapbooks, ledgers, memos, photographs, awards, and correspondence.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Tompkins County American Red Cross.; American Red Cross -- Administration.; Tompkins County (N.Y.). American Red Cross.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Minutes and Reports
Series II. Publications
Series III. Photographs
Series IV. Financial Records
Series V. Subject Files – Chronological Order
Series VI. Scrapbooks
Series VII. Awards
Series VIII. Memorabilia
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Minutes and Reports
  - Tompkins County Chapter-Board of Directors, Executive Committee, Administrative Committee, and various other committee meeting minutes; Treasurer's reports and other reports, 1917-1956 (Box 1, Folder 1-27)
  - Tompkins County Chapter-Board of Directors, Executive Committee, Administrative Committee, and various other committee meeting minutes; Treasurer's reports and other reports, 1956-1975 (Box 2, Folder 1-19)
  - Tompkins County Chapter-Annual Reports, Board Resolutions, 1995-1999 (Box 2, Folder 19A)
  - Tompkins County Chapter-Annual Meeting Minutes, October 2004 (Box 2, Folder 19B)
  - Tompkins County Chapter-Annual Meeting Minutes, 2005-2011 (Box 4, Folder 5,7,9-10,14-15,18)
- Series II. Publications
  - First Aid Notebook, no date (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Manual on Hairdressing/Massage, no date (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Brochure "The Red Cross is Universal", no date (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - "The Red Cross at Work", 1917 (Box 6)
  - Textbook on Home Hygiene and Care of the Sick, 1918 (Box 6)
  - Report of the Men's Red Cross Drive, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Introduction to Case Work and Administration of Relief, July 1933 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - The Red Cross Courier, August 1935 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - First Aid Handbook, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - In the Wake of Disaster; An Episode in the Life of Nature's Little People, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Nursing Service Manual, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Volunteer Nurse's Aide Service Manual, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - 100 Years of Reflections-First Presbyterian Church-Story of the Friendship Center, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Courier-Chapter Newsletter, 1992-1998 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Courier-Chapter Newsletter, 1999-2005 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Newsletter produced for 80th Anniversary, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - 125th Anniversary Booklet "Defining Moments in History 1881-2006", 2004 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - National American Red Cross Publications, Various Dates (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Series III. Photographs
  - Junior Red Cross 21st National Convention Dinner in Philadelphia-Panorama, June 1946 (Box 9)
  - Flood Related, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Various People, 1990s (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Staff and Board Members, 1990s (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Various People and Events, 1990s (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Various People and Events, 1990-2000 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Various Events and Meetings, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Series IV. Financial Records
  - Accounting Book, 1917-1926 (Box 9)
  - Recipts, 1920s (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Receipts, 1930s (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Expense Reports, 1925-1927 (Box 3, Folder 3-4)
  - Expense Reports, 1928-1934 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Cash Ledger, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Accounts, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Accounts, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Chart of Accounts, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Chart of Accounts, 1975-1978 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous Journals, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Series V. Subject Files – Chronological Order
  - Historical Timeline and Events-Tompkins County Chapter (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Historical Highlights of the Tompkins County Chapter, 1917-1981 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Lists of items received by Red Cross and where they came from, 1918-1919 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence/Memos/Radio Broadcasts, 1940s (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Certificate of Honor, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Ticket for 100th Anniversary of Tompkins County Chapter, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Press Release, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Inventory, 1969-1972 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Emergency Community Shelter, 1980s (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Articles and Memos-Tompkins County Chapter, 1980-1999 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Award Certificates and Proclamations, 1985-2006 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Friendship Center History, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Harlem Rockets Game-Sponsored by Red Cross, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - "September 12th" About Sculpture Donated to Tompkins County Red Cross, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Tompkins County Disaster Response Plan, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 31-33)
  - Partnering to Address Food Needs in a Disaster, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Tompkins County Chapter-Newspaper clippings, publications, 2002-2004 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Iraq War-Response, May 2003 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Midwest/Southeast Tornados-Response, May 2003 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Hurricane Isabel-Response, September 2003 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - California Wildfires-Response, October 2003 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Panel Discussion on Emergency Management for Seniors-Response, October 2003 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Volunteer and Fund Raising Information, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper clippings/Press releases, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 2-3)
  - Disaster Operations Summary Report, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Tompkins County Chapter-Reports, Newspaper clippings, Memos, Calendars, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Special Communications Task Force-Correspondence, memos, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Tompkins County Chapter-Reports, Minutes of Meetings, Memos, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Kendal Exhibit, February 2007 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Tompkins County Chapter-Meeting Minutes, Blood Services, Memos, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Tompkins County Chapter-Meeting Minutes, Volunteer Recognition, Newspaper Clippings, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Press Releases, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Radio Spots, 2008-2009 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Board Orientation Handbook, 2009 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Tompkins County Chapter-Meeting Minutes, Reports, Newspaper Clippings, 2009 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Tompkins County Chapter-Meeting Minutes, Reports, Newspaper Clippings, 2010 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - E-mails, 2011 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - News Releases, 2011 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Tompkins County Chapter-Reports, Memos, Newspaper Clippings, 2011 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - News Releases, 2011 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - News Releases, 2012 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Series VI. Scrapbooks
  - Scrapbook, 1917-1919 (Box 5)
  - Scrapbook, 1919-1925 (Box 5)
  - Scrapbook, 1931-1932 (Box 5)
  - Scrapbook, 1941-1945 (Box 5)
  - Scrapbook, 1942-1943 (Box 5)
  - Scrapbook-Ithaca's War Effort with Red Cross, 1944-1945 (Box 9)
  - Scrapbook, 1944-1945 (Box 5)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1945-1946 (Box 6)
  - Scrapbook-Blood Program, 1951-1961 (Box 7)
  - Scrapbook-Korean War, 1950-1954 (Box 7)
  - Scrapbook-Administration, 1950-1954 (Box 7)
  - Scrapbook, 1953-1955 (Box 7)
  - Scrapbook-Administration, 1954-1958 (Box 7)
  - Scrapbook-Administration, 1958-1965 (Box 7)
  - Scrapbook, 1961-1971 (Box 7)
  - Scrapbook, 1965-1973 (Box 7)
  - Scrapbook, 1972-1977 (Box 6)
  - Scrapbook-Newspaper Clippings, 1987 (Box 8)
  - Scrapbook-Newspaper Clippings, 1988-1995 (Box 8)
  - Scrapbook-Red Cross Mailings, 1991-1992 (Box 8)
  - Scrapbook-Newspaper Clippings, 1991-1997 (Box 8)
- Series VII. Awards
  - Plaque-Community Leader-Room Furnished by Contributions in Memory of Natalie Miller, 1976 (Box 8)
  - Plaque-Eastern New York Territory Honor Chapter Sward, 1986-1992 (Box 8)
  - Plaque-Walk America, 1991 (Box 8)
  - David Malcom Award to Terry Garahan and Lt. John Beau Saul, 2002 (Box 8)
  - Good Neighbor Award, 2007 (Box 8)
- Series VIII. Memorabilia
  - Diaries, 1933-1937 (Box 6)
  - Guest Book, 1955 (Box 6)
  - Cardboard American Junior Red Cross Carton (Box 6)
  - Mission Statement of the American Red Cross (Box 8)
  - Map depicting Red Cross in the World, 1963 (Map-case Folder 1)